All right, so what we're looking at is the price run in its entirety, some of the features that we look at, etc.
Just to put together the CPS series, really, so we're going to start off from this low here.
Essentially, what's happened is prior to this low, preceding that low, we've seen offers, offers, offers, ultimately push lower.
Every time price extended out to the downside, price would draw back in, back up the extension leg, fill it.
There's more than enough sellers at the most low.
base of inventory, in this case in the downtrend, sell inventory, and you continue pushing
with the downtrend. So here we picked up sellers, ran down, all right? Offers dry off, because
we're extending by this low, there's some buy liquidity here. Offers dry off price draws
back up the extension leg and there's more than enough sell liquidity inside this leg, inside
this practical liquidity base and of course sellers continue to push, right? Same happens here. Price
runs out, draws back in.
than of sellers price runs out draws back in more than of sellers price runs out draws
back in and now we have a shift in behavior where every time previously it drew back into the
last inventory of sell liquidity in the move down it was able to continue pushing to new
lows but in this instance because of how far prices travel to the downside and the level
price is picking up as in what low this or the liquidity this low is picking up now
whatever inventory of cell liquidity is left inside this last core area of
dual flow shelf is unable to push price down to new lows okay so we have a
response price ultimately it picks up whatever cell liquidity is inside the shelf
picks it up deals it off but the strength and the impetus behind this cell
this injection of cell liquidity is not able to materially push past whatever
buy liquidity has just entered the market down here so buy liquidity entered
this cell liquidity here is a battle this is a to go a war previously sellers won the tug-of-war
won it won it the further the cell liquidity the further the move travel to the downside the
weaker the sell liquidity gets the thinner the cell liquidity runs price cleared out these
lows extended comes back into shelf okay the last core area of sell liquidity responds can't
push to new lows bids continue to step in bids continue to step in low liquid state causes a shift
and price runs out. Now there's a shift in momentum. There's a shift in dynamics where buyers are
taking control and the same thing happens here. The sell liquidity is picking up sell liquidity,
picking up sell liquidity, but there's weakness in sellers now because of where buyers are pushed to.
They've literally changed the momentum. Price accumulates, it's a price pause, extremely inefficient
extension to the upside. I bet this is pinging off a level on the left. Look. Yeah, so we're actually
pinning off this apex-ish area all right well this whole area is an apex but there's a
fractal liquidity base inside of this apex because price is fractal and we extended extremely
inefficiently past these highs often bids have dried off and prices just drawn back in
the extension leg but still bids continue to come in i would assume there's a small
fractal there bids continue to step in new range price runs out bids dry
off, price draws back in, okay, this is the last core area of buy inventory, holding price
up, and there's more than not liquidity to push it, okay, bids drive off again, price
draws back in, it tries to, a response of this clean breaking point, but ultimately it goes back
to this core base, and again, there's more liquidity in this last deal flow area to
continue pushing price. Now, bids are picked up, price runs out, comes back to the last
core area, pushes again. This is the new area of deal flow.
flow. The last core area of dealing, price runs out. It doesn't basically, it doesn't fully fill it,
but often it will come back, fill it, it's picking up liquidity and it's more than enough to
continue pushing it. The fact that it did not fill it, okay, and it ultimately pushes to new
highs, it's going to show that price is getting really inefficient, okay, because it's leaving
these inefficiencies. But price, a bit of cumulate, price runs out, comes back, okay, more than enough
to continue pushing if price runs out comes back more than enough liquidity to
continue pushing to the upside at the last inventory okay at the last inventory and
then price accumulates price runs out okay runs again now this time when
price returns it tries to respond but ultimately it goes through it okay which now has
shown us that there's a shift in behavior where bids were successfully pushing
and pushing and pushing and pushing and pushing here and now there's not enough liquidity in this
area to continue pushing price up so this again is the shelf the shelf is defined as the last
core area of inventory that needs to hold up to continue pushing price along so this area held
up that was the last core area of inventory this area held up that was the last core area of inventory
to continue pushing price up now this is the last core area of inventory it needs to
the whole to continue pushing price up and oh shit it doesn't right price goes through it that
causes a shift in the state um ultimately you know there's going to be shelves on different time
frames but one could classify this is the whole area of the last core area of dealing that is the
whole of it price comes already picked up the middle so it comes to the bottom again whatever
liquidity is remaining inside of this shelf is failing to continue pushing price to new highs
These are all signs of weakness in price and price goes to the weaker side.
But again, look at what area this picked up.
It picked up the highs, right?
Basically, visited the liquidity at these highs.
Once price starts breaking past this shelf,
there's another shift in momentum where sellers take control
and prices trades through all of these levels,
primarily because of how they were picked up on the way up, right?
So we had liquidity, the top was picked, the bottom,
to wash this area at the top and the middle.
The same applies with this.
The top was already picked.
We came and picked it up again and delta off.
So this area is getting drained.
And, you know, we're going to look at later anyway.
The differences in price delivery and what the implications are for how much
liquidity is left over in different instances.
But we extend all the way back down to this core area.
So again, this is different, okay, to these mid-price run levels.
This is where the move was initiated and broke to the oxide, essentially.
price visits it visits the bottom side the response draws all the way back up this weakness in
price to the to sell liquidity base the bottom was picked on the way down so price goes towards
the middle but the point in me um basically just experience what's going on is to just show you
how consistently price is swinging from one side to the other where on an entry day basis
anyway and on a high time trip as well but a price is just swinging and there's
multitude of price swings and there's a lot of price features that we can
engage with throughout the day so let's take this price run for example is up and
down basically from about 12 p.m. until the next day you know yeah so this is 12 p.m. this is 12
p.m. the next day so more than 24 hours a price swing on a five-minute shot
Bids push past here, the shelf, so bids to control, price runs out, this is a pattern of
self-similarity inside the broader one, okay, so bids pushed out, there's a leg of inefficiency
there, bids dry off, price draws back down, picks up of bids from here, and runs again,
okay, runs really inefficiently, bids dry off, draws back down, picks up liquidity, runs again.
Of course, inside of these moves, we have patterns of self-similarity on a smaller scale, but
this price rings inside there with all the relative features that we've covered in this series
anyway but ultimately price runs again extends to new highs this is now the last core area of
inventory price bleeds back down to the shelf there's not enough liquidity in the buy
shelf and the buy there's not enough by liquidity in the shelf to continue pushing it to new
highs ultimately what price does is it retest the apex sellers continue to pressure
we push past the shelf, shift in the state of liquidity here, and now there's a change in
behaviour. We're on the way of bids were pushing, now sellers are pushing, price extends down,
clips on residual liquidity, draws back up and sellers sell into any values. Price extends past
this low, clip some liquidity somewhere anywhere in the lower time frame, the pocket's there.
And of course, we're starting to see every time price extends past lows, it draws back
up to fill the extension modestly anyway but of course sellers continue to
pressure price lower primarily because these middle spots have weak areas of
liquidity when prices coming back through them so we see this again low price
extends draws back up low extends draws back up these are generally going to be
pinging off some residual liquidity areas like this price extends okay
passes lows extends comes and grab liquidity and this time
runs up deeper into cell inventory here okay so now we're draining whatever
cell liquidity is pushing down with this and of course again inside of here
we have just to give you an idea one big swing a smaller swing inside
that smaller swing there swing there and then you have swings there there
there there's another swing inside the big one and then there swings there
there literally just fucking everyone okay and that's like the tempo and the rhythm
price moves in. So when you have a big move, think of it as a big move like this is composed
on the lower time frame, smaller moves, price swings inside it. All right. But when you start
to observe these now, you basically want to find them, okay, on a chart, mark them out, mark all
the features out. And generally, because of what we've discussed, we should be able to relate
with the liquidity principles that be applied to the market and why it's relevant for each
feature. So in other words, you know, price going to the weaker side, the shelf failing to push
price to new highs is showing weakness, okay, in the buy liquidity that pushed this price up.
And of course, price draws back down. Or things like inefficient extensions get filled. So this
is inefficient, it extended, really inefficiently, and ultimately you've filled it. It tried to
anyway. We extended, we filled it. We extended past these lows. We filled it. We extend past these
lows, fill it. Extend past these lows, fill it. All these details you really kind of
should be mocking out any way going through in your mind.
But then once you have a firm understanding
of all the liquidity principles
and how to spot these price swings,
then you can go in and start trying to take trades.
So you see price extend past the high.
The liquidity factor on the left,
you can then take a pretend trade
and basically get a feel and try to exercise
how it feels fading fast price movement.
If that's not your staff, you can take apex retest.
If that's not your style, you can try to trade in breakouts.
And essentially what you're gonna find
is some trades have a negative expectancy,
which is a good thing to know.
And some trades have a positive expectancy,
again, which is a good thing to know.
That way you can differentiate between shit and bad trade
because you've gone and done your work,
you've done your due diligence,
and you know which areas of a pricing
are highly, highly responsive,
like the apexes, the apexes.
You know what price behavior is highly, highly probable
where price extends and efficiently it fills it.
We're extending, we ultimately fill it.
And on a micro scale as well, we have extensions, builds, extensions, builds, inefficient
price runs, you know, there's inefficiency there, price tries to fill it.
It's inefficiency back in the way open price builds it.
There's just a multitude of things that we're going to cover later on in the series, sorry,
later on in the course basically, and the mentoring, but right now it's just a case of building
scale, finding these price features, trying to understand why these price features are
relevant and trying to get a gauge of why price is doing why is doing okay yeah any
questions let me know